Mohamed Moanis Abdellatif Ali

Software Engineer



SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with 2 years of experience. I am a pragmatic developer who can figure his way around, work independently and get the work done. I love to automate things that I do and to generate new ideas to improve the process, the team and the product.

EXPERIENCE

Mentor Graphics - Software Development Engineer

Sep 2016 - PRESENT

- I am working on the full stack development of a CAD tool.
- I design, develop, test and document features based on customers' requirements.

Mentor Graphics - Intern

Feb 2016 - Sep 2016

 I worked on a major performance improvement project in our geometry processing engine that resulted in a 4x speedup using C++.

AvidBeam - Thesis Work Intern

Mar 2016 - June 2016

- I worked on a computer vision and image processing research project using C++, OpenCV and Matlab.
- I used Ruby-on-Rails, JS(Backbone.js), HTML, CSS, MongoDB to develop a web application for our video big data analysis engine.

AvidBeam - Intern

June 2015 - Sep 2015

- I used C++ to develop a video transcoding tool that can save up to 90% of bandwidth.
- I developed image processing algorithms on GPUs with C++ and OpenCL.

EDUCATION

Cairo University - BSc Electrical Engineering

Oct 2011 - July 2016

- Major: Communication & Computer Engineering. GPA: 3.4 (B+)
- Thesis: "A system for vehicles' recognition with surveillance cameras". Grade: 4 (A)